Jesper Kjeldgaard



theispr@gmail.com

For the past 10 years I have worked with full-stack development in several startups and companies, mostly revolving around Ruby on Rails applications. Latest as a CTO and co-founder of a startup where I built a web-application and marketing site, as well as being involved in daily operations, finance and management.

My drive comes from delivering value to the business, and I love being part of solving problems from initial ideas to deployment. Besides having solid experience in building web-applications, I also have experience with marketing (automation), finance, analytics, mobile development and leading small teams.

If you have any ideas or projects that you think could benefit from my skills and knowledge, or just want to have a chat, please don't hesitate to get in touch.

Experience

<u>Grafik on Demand</u>, Co-founder and CTO. February 2017 - Juli 2019 (2 years 4 months) Built a web-application for ordering and delivering graphic designs online.

<u>Webyard</u> (Owner), Software Consultant. February 2015 - February 2017 (2 years) Working with Android, Ruby, Rails and Web technologies for several clients. My clients include <u>Skyscanner</u>, <u>Bitsilk</u> and <u>GoMore</u>.

<u>HouseTrip</u>, Software Engineer. April 2013 - December 2014 (1 year 8 months)

Working on housetrip.com, a large Rails application with many moving parts. I was involved in several big projects like; a responsive redesign of several key pages, introducing feature flags, migrating our CI to TravisCI and lots of initiatives to improve conversion rates.

At HouseTrip I was also a Lead Software Engineer in a team of 5 from 10/2014 to 09/2015. During this time I managed 2-3 engineers, helped the PM plan and estimate projects and in general focused on keeping the team on track and thriving.

Evently, Software Engineer. November 2011 - March 2013 (1 year 5 months)

At Evently I have worked on making online event marketing easier. This includes adding features to and maintaining a large SaaS Rails application, and building new API consuming/providing applications. The technologies I used whilst at Evently include: Redis, MongoDB, RSpec, SOA, EC2/Heroku, Postgresql and EmberJS.

One project I've worked on whilst at Evently was a service to distribute events to numerous listing sites using Capybara. Another project was creating public event pages for events. The

public event pages are managed from a separate application which updates the pages through an API. Most projects were developed using Kanban.

Internships whilst studying.

Harmonypark. March 2011 – September 2011 (7 months): At Harmonypark I worked on a large time management Rails application.

Capana. May 2009 – September 2010 (1 year 5 months): Developing web applications internally and for customers using PHP and MySQL.

Education

MSc. Internet Application Development. October 2010 - November 2011

Middlesex University, London, United Kingdom.

Grade: 2:1 (Pass with Merit)

Notable projects: Ruby web-server. Web-based file-storage service.

BSc. Software Engineering. September 2007 - June 2010

Aalborg University, Denmark.

Grade: B average. A in my final project.

Notable projects: An Implicitly parallel programming language (Java). A social network for

universities (C#/ASP.NET).

Technical Skills Summary

• Languages: Ruby, JavaScript, Java.

Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, ReactJS, Android.

• Databases: Postgresql, Redis.

• Platforms: AWS and Heroku.

• Testing: RSpec, Jest and JUnit.

Msc: HTML, Sass/css.

More information

thejspr.com github.com/thejspr linkedin.com/in/jesperkjeldgaard